♪〜
〜♪
Hey, Vash!
（ミリオンズ･ナイヴズ）
よう ヴァッシュ
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
ああ…
Now everything linking
you and Rem is gone.
（ナイヴズ）
これで 君とレムをつなぐものは
すべてなくなったね
Is that...
Is that your excuse?!
それが… それが理由か！
（ナイヴズ）君は この100年
何を学んできた？
What have you learned
these past 100 years?
The scars carved into you
will never regenerate.
その体に刻み込まれた傷は
再利用もできない
You are living proof
of the folly of human trash.
ゴミどもの愚かな行為
そのものだよ
You're wrong.
They're all alive.
お前は間違ってる
みんな生きてる…
生きてるんだ！
Alive!
Why grow up if you only
grow more sentimental?
（ナイヴズ）
おセンチなところだけ
成長しても—
しょうがないだろうが
...you good-for-nothing
weepy-faced kid!
このメソメソ泣いてるだけの
ガキが！
なっ…
ぐあ くっ ああ…
（ヴァッシュの荒い息遣い）
うあ…
（指を鳴らす音）
W-What's this light?
こ… この光は…
It's something
you and I can do.
（ナイヴズ）
これが僕と君の能力だ
さあ なぎ払おう
Now, let's dispose
of all the trash.
すべてのゴミを
（ヴァッシュ）
あっ ぐあああー！
ああっ ぐああ…
あああ…
Are you going
to shoot me again?
（ナイヴズ）また僕を狙うのか
（ヴァッシュ）あああー！
Are you really going
to shoot me again...
また僕を狙うというのか
ヴァッシュ！
...Vash?!!!
Eriks?
（リィナ）エリクス… エリクス
（ドアが開く音）
How long are you going to
to stay in bed? Get up!
（リィナ）
いつまで寝てれば気が済むの
早く起きなさい
Eriks!
エリクス エリクス！
（市民たち）乗せてくれ！
乗せてってください！
（市民１）乗せてくれ！
Let me on!
At least take me
to the next town!
（市民２）せめて隣町まで頼む！
カネはあるから乗せてくれ！
I have money! Let me on!
こうしているあいだにも—
He might try to take the town
while we stand here arguing!
あの男が町に乗り込んでくるかも
しれねえんだ
But you need
a ticket to ride...
（車掌）
しかし 正規の切符がなければ…
Don't you get it yet?!
（市民２）
そんな話をしてるんじゃねえよ
いくら要るって聞いてるんだ！
Just name your price!
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
えっ…
Wait, don't go!!
（市民たち）待ってくれ！
乗せてってくれ！
Let us on!!
There's a lot of tension
in this town.
えらい緊張感のある町やなあ
I haven't seen you before.
Did you come in on that bus?
（マスター）見ない顔だな
今のバスで来たのか？
- That's right.
- You have my sympathy.
そや
（マスター）気の毒に
あんた もうこの町から
出られんよ
You will never leave this town.
（銃声）
（爆発音）
あっ…
This town is under
siege by bandits.
（マスター）この町は今
郎党に包囲されている
Not only that...
しかも そのバックには—
...they say Vash the Stampede
is running the show.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが
いるって話だ
The sheriff went to negotiate, but
came back doubled his weight in lead.
（マスター）
交渉に出向いた保安官も—
鉛球で体重を２割増やして
戻ってきた
Once you walk into this town,
you're here for good.
この町に入れば
二度と出られぬクモの巣だよ
The legendary gunman,
huh? Is that true?
伝説のガンマンねえ
ホンマなんか？ それ
Don't ask me.
（マスター）さあな
The man who incinerated
two of the seven cities...
（マスター）
七都市の２つを灰に変え—
人類初の局地災害に
指定された男
...designated as mankind's
first localized Act of God.
Some even say he put
that hole in the moon...
あの月の大穴まで
やつの仕業だってんだ
...but you'd have to be
crazy to believe that.
真に受けるほうが
どうかしてる
（ウルフウッド）せやけど
伝説の真偽に関係なく—
Setting the thing
about the legend aside...
...this town needs help, bad.
この町は 脅威にさらされとる
ゆうわけや
By the way, what is that?
ところで あんたのそれは？
I'm a traveling priest.
（ウルフウッド）
巡回牧師やっとんねん
I'm glad you're here.
ちょうど よかった
We don't need anything formal,
just help with the funerals.
略式でいい
葬式を手伝ってくれ
They took out our chaplain
a short while back.
こないだ
牧師もやられちまったんでね
うん？
ちょ ちょ… ちょっと
何のつもり！
Hey...
...what's the big idea?!
何だ リィナか
Oh, it's only Lina.
I'm not "only" Lina!!
Let go of me, Eriks!
“何だ”じゃないわよ
エリクスも放して もう…
What's the big hurry, Lina?
何 慌ててんだ リィナ
I'm sorry, bartender...
Will you hide me?
マスター ごめんね かくまって
What did you do?
何やらかした？
She doesn't know
when to quit!
（エリクス）
リィナは やりすぎなんだよ
He was just poking
a little fun...
ちょっと
からかわれたくらいでさ
That pedophile
had it coming to him!
殴られて当然よ あのロリコン！
I mean, just because
he fondled her butt...
連中に尻 触られたくらいで
いたっ
Keep your mouth shut!
（リィナ）ベラベラしゃべるな
Does that mean?
No, surely not...
…てことは まさか
I'm afraid so. I don't think
they saw me come in here, but...
そうなの
この店に入ったのは
見られてないと思うんだけど…
Hey, that's not funny!
（男性１）
おいおい 冗談じゃねえぞ
If what she says is true...
（男性２）だとしたら…
（マスター）あっ…
（男性たち）うわっ
Give me back my lunch!
どないしてくれんねん これ
Where is the little girl...
（モヒカン）僕ちゃんの
このラブリーな お顔に—
...who struck my lovely face
with her heel?!
かかとくれた小娘は どこだ！
It was more like
an entire foot.
…ていうか あれは蹴りだね
Quiet, you!
（リィナ）うるさい
I see. That is a fine print.
The kid's got talent.
（ウルフウッド）なるほど
キレイに入っとんな
筋ええで このガキ
この男が店に入るのを
見たっつってんの
This man claims he saw
her enter this bar!
If he's wrong, I'll wring his neck
here and now for his trouble!
ガセだったら おわびに
今ここで絞め殺すわ
In any event, it will
be settled in 3 seconds!
どっちにするにも ３秒以内で
ケリがつくってわけね
３…
3!
２…
2!
One!
１！
ぬおっ？
Eriks!
エリクス
ちょ… ちょっと待ってよ
Wait a second!
Oh, hey! We're really sorry
you didn't find it funny.
いやあ ホントすまなかったな
冗談が通じなくてさ
She's only a little 12 year-old.
Come on, have a heart.
何分 まだ12歳の女の子だ
大目に見てやってく…
Yeek!
こわー
ガキのほうを出しなよ
Send out the kid.
That I can't do!
そりゃできない
After all, you look
like you wanna kill her.
だって あんたたち
殺すって面(つら)してるもん
I won't ask for a free favor.
If I do this...
タダとは言わないよ これで…
あっ
...will you let her off?
（エリクス）
勘弁してもらえねえか
Eriks...
エリクス…
That's not good enough.
（モヒカン）
それだけじゃ足りないんだわ
Since you're on all fours,
you could at least act like a dog...
せめて犬のまねでも
してもらわなきゃ—
こっちも収まりがつかんでしょ？
もちろん裸になって
...buck-naked, of course!
なっ…
（男性たちのどよめき）
（男性３）おい マジか…
Do you mean that?
Keep your word.
（エリクス）
ホントだな？ 約束 守れよ
（男性たち）ああ…
You don't have to do that!!
そんなことすることないわよ
やめて エリクス！
Don't do it, Eriks!
Eriks!!
エリクス！
Eriks...
エリクス…
ヘヘヘッ… ぬおっ？
あっ…
（リィナ）うう…
It's not your fault, sweetie.
お嬢ちゃんが
悪いわけやあらへん
It's what he wanted.
あの男が望んだことや
But I...
（リィナ）でも…
That's just how it is.
そういうことなんや
（エリクス）ワオー
ワンワン ワンワン
ワン ワワン ワン
Thank you for the entertainment!
I'll leave you a big, fat tip!
いい余興になったわ
チップも多めにはずんでやるよ
おっ？
ぬお… フッ 戻るぞ
Let's go.
ハハッ
Shoot him.
撃て
（発砲音）
ERI KS!!
（リィナ）エリクス！
What's all this?
（医師）何じゃ 何じゃ
He's been shot!
Please help him, doctor!!
（リィナ）撃たれたの
お願い 先生！
（医師）エリクスか
何度目じゃ こいつ
Eriks again? How many
times has he been here?
I can't tell if
the bullet's out!
（男性４）
弾が貫通してるかどうか
分からねえ
If you had to choose between your life
and your pride, which would you choose?
（ガンマン１）
プライドと命 天秤(てんびん)にかけてよ—
お前なら どっち取る？
I'd never be able to strip
and bark like a dog.
（ガンマン２）
裸で犬のまねかよ
よくやるぜ まったく…
It's the perfect talent
for a wimp like Eriks!
（ガンマン１）
腰抜けのエリクスには
ちょうどいいぜ
（ガンマンたち）うわっ
その腰抜けのおかげで
命拾うたんは誰なんじゃ コラ！
Thanks to that "wimp,"
you ingrates are still alive!!
Eriks! Eriks!
（シェイル）
エリクス… エリクス
Grandma!
（リィナ）おバアちゃん
Eriks...
エリクス…
It's all right, Grandma.
The bullet was out.
大丈夫よ おバアちゃん
弾は貫通してたの
He's one lucky devil.
まったく 運の強いやつじゃ
I don't know who this
legendary gunman thinks he is...
伝説のガンマンだか—
なんだか
知らないけど—
...but does he have the right
to steal what little family is left...
この年寄りから—
小さな家族まで奪う
権利を—
...to an old woman like me?!
そいつは
持っているのかね
God dammit!
チクショウ！
Hey, ma'am!
（ガンマン３）
お… おい バアさん
やめろよ そんな体で
Stop it! You're too old!
You won't last
two seconds against him!
（医師）
お前さんが行ったところで
かなう相手じゃない
Let me go! All right,
who will go in my place?!
（シェイル）放しな！
じゃあ 代わりにあんたたちが
行ってくれるとでも言うのかい
ほら 見ろ
とんだ腰抜けどもだ
See? You're all
a bunch of cowards.
You're far too young
to order me around!!
私に意見しようなんて
10年早いよ！
You're going to get
yourself killed, you old bat!
（ガンマン３）
こ… 殺されちまうって
言ってんだよ クソババア
うるさい！
Shut up!
Stop it, Grandma!
やめて おバアちゃん
- Lina...
- It's my fault.
リィナ…
私のせいなの
If I had stayed away from them,
he wouldn't have...
私が あいつらに
ちょっかい出したから—
エリクスが… エリクスが…
...he wouldn't have...
At any rate, keep the noise down.
Other patients are trying to recover.
（医師）
とにかく 静かにするんじゃ
ほかの患者の傷に障る
I'm so sorry, doctor...
（シェイル）
ああ… すまないね 先生
No, I understand how you feel.
I'll have Eriks moved to the ward.
（医師）なあに 気持ちは分るよ
エリクスは
病室に移しておくから
頼むよ
Thank you.
Let's go fetch him
a change of clothes, Lina.
着替えを取りに行こうか リィナ
Yeah.
うん…
Let's roll him into the ward.
病室に移動するぞ
うん？ 何じゃ？
What? You can leave, too.
He'll be all right now.
お前さんも早く出て行きなさい
もう大丈夫じゃ
I know that.
I want to help.
分かっとるがな
手伝おう言うとんのや
フウ… いつまで寝とる？
How long are
you gonna sleep?
Wake up, you!
起きんかい コラ！
（医師）ケガ人に何するか！
（ウルフウッド）はがが…
What are you doing
to my patient?!
Doctor, doctor!!
（看護婦）あっ 先生 先生！
うん？
What's this?
Are you conscious already?
何じゃ 何じゃ
もう意識が戻ったんか？
Sorry, doc. Could you leave
the room for a little while?
（ヴァッシュ）先生 悪い
少し外してくれないか？
あっ ああ…
無理させちゃあかんぞ
Sure.
Don't let him strain himself.
（ドアの開閉音）
Long time, no see...
久しぶりやな
...Vash the Stampede.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
I finally found you, you idiot.
（ウルフウッド）
やっと見つけたで このアホが
What's a legendary guy like you
doing in a place like this?
伝説の男が こないなとこで
何しとるんや？
Stop it. I could have destroyed
the planet with that gun.
（ヴァッシュ）
やめてくれよ 俺は—
あの銃で この星を
なぎ払っていたかもしれないんだ
There's a blank in my memory.
I can't explain what I did.
しかも 記憶が飛んでいて
何をしたか分からない
（ウルフウッド）けど あれは
お前がやったことや 違うか？
Maybe, but it was you,
wasn't it?
Yes, it was me.
（ヴァッシュ）ああ そうさ
My fragmentary visions,
but more than anything...
断片的なビジョンと—
そして 何より
心の中にある確信が語っている
...something inside tells me
I'm the one.
I'm the one who put
that hole in the 5th moon.
（ヴァッシュ）
あの５番目の月に
穴を開けたのは俺だ
フウ
And you're so afraid
of what you can do...
…で そのあまりの脅威に
恐れをなして—
...you're living
in easy retirement?
今は 気楽な
隠居生活っちゅうわけかい
I only wanted
to live quietly...
（ヴァッシュ）ただ静かに
暮らしたかっただけだよ
...with a different name,
and a different way of life.
名前も生き方も変えて…
うっ… あんた
何しに ここに来たんだい？
Why are you here?
Are you here to laugh at me?
こんな俺を笑いに来たのかい？
I came to take you away.
（ウルフウッド）
お前を連れていくためや
どこへ？
To where?
If you're asking for
a final destination...
最終的に どこへ言うたら
そら分からん
...I don't know. However...
そやけど お前の力が
必要になったっちゅうことや
...I do know that I need your help.
I turned Augusta upside-down
looking for you.
そのために オーガスタ中
ひっくり返して捜したんやで
Have you ever met
a guy named Marlon?
お前 マーロンと
会(お)うたことあるんか？
I mentioned I knew you,
and he fixed it for free.
知り合いや言うたら
ロハにしてくれたで
Why? Why are you
giving me this?
なぜだ… なぜ これを…
I thought you'd need it.
（ウルフウッド）必要や思てな
I want... I want
to live my life here with them.
（ヴァッシュ）俺は…
俺は ここでみんなと…
Why was he hospitalized
the last time?
（シェイル）この前は
なんで入院したんだっけかね？
He tried to stop a violent drunk
at the bar and got punched himself.
（リィナ）酒場で暴れた男を
取り押さえようとして—
反対に殴られた
And the time before that?
（シェイル）その前は？
He fell off a thomas.
（リィナ）トマから落っこちた
You be sure to thank him!
（シェイル）エリクスに
ちゃんと言うんだよ
Yeah... I know.
うん… 分かってる
あっ
Are you okay?
（リィナ）大丈夫？ 君
うっ…
（シェイル）
なんて体してるんだい
You're in horrible shape!
You poor thing...
You must have been through a lot.
かわいそうに よっぽど
大変な目に遭ってきたんだね
It's okay...
You'll be safe here.
大丈夫 ここにいれば安全だよ
So you're staying, huh?
（ウルフウッド）
ここにおるんやな？
Whenever I step in,
people die.
（ヴァッシュ）
俺が動けば 人が死ぬ
All right.
分かった
If you want it bad enough
to give up everything else...
ほかのもん
全部 投げ出してでも—
欲しいもんがあるんやったら
そうしたらええ
...then go for it.
なあ…
Say...
...are you familiar with
a town called Carcases?
カルカサスいう町
知っとるか？
It's a tiny town
in Southern Cornelia.
南コーネリアにある
ちっちゃい町や
Something strange happened
there six months ago.
実は そこで半年前
妙な事件が起こった
Its residents suddenly
disappeared without a trace.
突然 住民が
根こそぎ失踪したんや
Everything in the town
looked completely normal...
（ウルフウッド）何もかもが
すべて日常をとどめたまんま—
...only, the people
had vanished.
住人だけが
陽炎(かげろう)のように消えてしもた
The cavalry went in
and combed the place over...
騎兵隊が入って
捜し回ったんやけど—
...but didn't find a soul.
人っ子一人おらん
One cavalryman, however,
did discover something odd...
けど ある隊員が
１つだけ妙な物を発見しおった
...a man's name painted on
the monument in the town square.
中央広場のモニュメントに
書き殴られた ある男の名前をな
It was in red,
and they say it read...
それは赤い字で
こう書いてあったそうや
...Knives.
“ナイヴズ”ってな
Knives.
ナイヴズ…
Whenever I step in, Destiny homes in
on the smell of blood and gun smoke.
俺が動けば—
運命が 血と硝煙のにおいを
嗅ぎつける
It only creates
mountains of debris.
生み出されるのは
ガレキの山だけだ
（ヴァッシュ）
あっ ああ… うっ
（レム･セイブレム）
ヴァッシュ　ナイヴズを…
Vash...
... take care of Knives!
Rem! Rem!!
レム！ レムー！
（ヴァッシュ）
僕は… どうしたらいいんだ
What should I do?
Your gun! Give me
your gun, hurry!!
（シェイル）
銃を貸しとくれ 銃を　早く！
What is it, Gramma Sheryl?
（市民３）何だよ どうした
シェイルバアさん
They've got Lina!
（シェイル）
リィナが やつらに…
（市民３）えっ なんだって！
（シェイル）早く貸しな！
- What?!
- Give it here, quick!
Wait, Sheryl!
Don't throw your life away!
（市民３）おい 待て バアさん
ムダ死にするだけだぞ
She's probably dead by now!
それに今頃 行ったって
もう殺されてるかも…
Don't argue,
just give me your gun!!!
（シェイル）
ゴチャゴチャ言ってないで
早く貸すんだよ！
Grandma! Grandma, wait!!
（市民３）
バアさん おい バアさん！
（ドアが開く音）
（ウルフウッド）うん？
（ヴァッシュ）俺さ
ホントに気に入ってたんだぜ—
You know, I...
...really was fond
of my life here.
今の生活
Them's the breaks.
しゃあないやろ
Someone's gotta get tough
or someone else is gonna cry.
誰かが牙にならんと
誰かが泣くことになるんや
They're both gone!
（市民３）二人がいないぞ
"Please don't look for us.
We're going to get Lina back."
“捜さないでください”
“リィナを
取り返しに行きます”って—
All by themselves?!
たった２人でか？
How many are there?
（ウルフウッド）相手の数は？
About 200.
ざっと200
100 each, huh?
That's a shame...
１人100人か 難儀なこっちゃな
H-Hey, don't kill anyone!
お… おい 絶対 殺すなよ
む… 無茶なこと言うな
Don't ask the impossible!!
Thou Shalt Not Kill!
“汝(なんじ) 殺すなかれ”だ
なんて聖職者だよ まったく
What the hell kind of
a churchman are you?!
ヘヘッ 何べんも
同じことぬかすな
Stop saying the same thing.
You're sounding
like your old self!
調子 戻ってきたやないか
（爆発音）
Eriks!
（リィナ）エリクス！
（エリクス）あっ
Slaughter 'em!!
ぶっ殺せ！
Let's do it.
（ウルフウッド）いくで
（ヴァッシュ）おう
I must have been
out of my mind...
（リィナ）よりによって
こんな薄汚いのに声かけたとは—
...to talk to someone
so filthy-looking.
どうかしてたわね 私
フフッ
Hey, did the two of them take care
of all these thugs by themselves?
（ガンマン１）
おい たった２人で—
このならず者たちを
すべて片づけたっていうのか？
I've never seen anyone
kick so much ass in my life.
（ガンマン２）見たことねえな
あんな べらぼうに強い連中はよ
So your mind is made up?
（シェイル）
決心はついたのかい？
Yeah. I think I will go...
（ヴァッシュ）うん
やっぱり出ていくことにするよ
... although I hate to
do this to you and Lina.
バアちゃんとリィナには
悪いけど…
Isn't there anything we can do?
（シェイル）
私らに何かできることは
ないのかい？
Tell me all about it.
全部 話しとくれよ
Thank you...
ありがとう
でも 聞いちゃダメだ
... but I can't. If I did,
you would be put in danger.
聞けば
危険にさらされる
We know you're going to wind up
alone in another alley somewhere.
そうやって また一人で
ボロボロになりに行くんだね
That hurts us the most
about your leaving.
私らには そのほうが
よっぽどつらいよ
I'm sorry.
（ヴァッシュ）ごめんな
Who would have guessed that Eriks
was actually Vash the Stampede?
（男性３）しっかし たまげたぜ
あのエリクスが
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだとは
Tell me about it!
（男性３）まったくだ
（男性４）しかも俺たちが—
And to think, all this time
we thought pig-man here was Vash!
ヴァッシュだと思わされてたやつが
このブタ野郎ときた
Hey, do you think he plans
to stay on in this town?
（男性５）なあ やつは
この町に居続けるつもりなのか？
Don't even go there!
（男性４）
やめてくれ タチが悪(わり)いぜ
Yeah! We ought to
run him out right now!
（男性３）
ああ 今すぐ追い出すべきだ
（髪を切る音）
（ウルフウッド）そうか…
お嬢ちゃん 泣いとったんか
I see...
...she cried, huh?
Maybe I was a little too pushy.
ちょっと
強引すぎたかもしれんな
You hardly need apologize.
（シェイル）何をいまさら…
Mr. Preacher, please
take good care of our Eriks.
牧師さん　エリクスを頼むよ
Unlike you, he's a bumbling
fool of a goody-goody.
あんたと違って 抜け目だらけの
お人よしなんだから
Lina and I realized
somewhere in our hearts...
リィナも私も 心のどこかでは
気付いていたはずなんだ
...we knew that Eriks would
probably leave us someday.
エリクスが いつまでも—
ここにいる種類の人間じゃない
ってことを
でも 家族をなくすことに
変わりはないんだ
But that doesn't change the fact that
we're losing a member of the family.
Please don't forget that.
どうか そのことを
忘れないでおくれ
堪忍な
I'm sorry.
I'm truly sorry, Grandmother.
ホンマ堪忍やで オバちゃん
（髪を切る音）
There.
（リィナ）はい 終わったよ
All done.
（すすり泣き）
リィナ…
Lina...
（リィナ）うう… うっ
Thank you.
ありがとう
I wanted to keep you safe...
（リィナ）守ってあげようと
思ってたのに—
...but it turned out
the other way around.
逆だったね
I was too weak.
私には 何の力もなかった
Don't be stupid.
バカ言うな
（リィナ）
ありがとう… ごめんなさい
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Those are both my lines.
どっちも俺のセリフだ
（リィナのすすり泣き）
Lina...
（ヴァッシュ）リィナ…
... thank you.
ありがとう
And goodbye, for now.
そして 今は さよならだ
♪〜
〜♪
A strong will
can stir the heart.
（ヴァッシュ）
強い意志は 心を奮い立たせる
But a will too strong
can limit the heart's visibility.
だが 強すぎる意志は
心の視界を極端に狭めてしまう
The sorrow of a man bereaved
of family turns into hate...
家族を失った男の悲しみが
憎しみとなり—
...which eventually transforms
into the intent to kill.
やがて殺意へと変貌する
The man's finger
reaches for the trigger.
男が銃の引き金に指を伸ばす
Sins change people.
Sin begets sin.
罪が人を変える 罪が罪を生む
Oh, but I...
...but I still want to believe!
ああ でも僕は…
それでも僕は信じたいんだ—
I want to believe in
the hearts that feel sin.
罪を感じる人の心を